Guide to the Department of History, Yale University, Senior Prize Essays
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- History senior essay prize winners, 2016; Accession 2017-A-025
  - American prize winners
    - Percival Clement Prize
      - Allread, William Tanner, "Chahta Anumpa Vlhpisa (Choctaw Constitution): Indigenous Governance in the Removal Era, 1825-1834;" adviser: Ned Blackhawk (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - European prize winners
    - Andrew White European Prize
      - Dubovoy, Alexander, "Kinds of Red: Jazz in Soviet Experience;" adviser: Sara Brinegar (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Winifred Sturley Prize
      - Bader, Jonah, "Resource Revolution: Timber, Fish, and the Coming of the American Revolution;" adviser: Steve Pincus (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - History of Science and Medicine prize winners
    - Rosen/Klein Prize
      - Vishwanath, Vivek, "Transforming Primary Care: How Multiphasic Health Services Redefined Care Delivery at Kaiser Permanente. 1948-1973;" adviser: John Harley Warner (Box 1, Folder 4)
        This essay was also the recipient of the John Addison Porter History Prize.
  - LAAA (Latin American, Africa, Asia & Middle East) prize winners
    - Andrew White LAAA Prize
    - Max Bildner Prize
    - Robert Gries Prize
- History senior essay prize winners, 2017; Accession 2017-A-069
  - American prize winners
    - Andrew D. White Prize
      - Echelman, Adam, "The Imperfect Refugees: The Foundations of Rightlessness for Salvadoran Asylum Seekers in the United States, 1980-1996" (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Edwin N. Small Prize
      - Yankowitz, Emily, "Creating an Inclusive National History Through Biographical Sketches (1607-1842): William Plumer's America" (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - George Washington Egleston Prize
      - Landsberg, Eva Brooks, ""The Sons of Liberty and the Sons of Slavery": Intra-Imperial Rivalry in the British Atlantic, 1730-1775" (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - John Addison Porter Prize
      - Armandroff, Olivia, "The Bookplate in its Golden Age: A Mark of Ownership Becomes an Advertisement for the Middle Class" (Box 1, Folder 6)
        This essay was also the recipient of the Richard Hegel Prize
      - Taft, Isabelle, "Spinning the New South: The Southern Textile Exposition and Regional Identity, 1915-1972" (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Percival Clement Prize
  - European prize winners
    - Andrew D. White Prize
      - Schaechter, Reyna, "Critical Examinations of "Zero Hour" in the Polish Jewish Community, 1944-1950" (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Winifred Sturley Prize
  - Other essay prize winners
    - Harvey M. Applebaum Prize
    - Diane E. Kaplan Prize
      - Pajka, Sarah, "Doctors, Death and Denial: The Origins of Hospice Care in 20th Century America" (Box 1, Folder 18)
- History senior essay prize winners, 2018; Accession 2019-A-0004
  - American prize winners
    - Andrew D. White Prize
      - Ewing-Nelson, Sinclair, "Gun Violence and Gun Control in Coleman Young's Detroit". (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Judt, Daniel, "The Reactionary Dilemma: George Fitzhugh and the Fight for a Southern Future, 1850-1870". (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - The Edwin W. Small Prize
      - Black, Griffin, "Lion at the Lectern: Frederick Douglass Becomes an Orator, 1938-1945". (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Ranieri, Kyle, "Restoring Hozho: Indigenous Constitutionalism in the Navajo Tribal Courts". (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - The George Washington Egleston American Prize
      - Samora, Chelsea, "Advancement in Every Direction, Except Suffrage: Female Anti-Suffragists and Conceptions of Political Womanhood in the United States, 1880-1920". (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - The John Addison Porter American History Prize
      - Raik, Rohan, "Para un Futuro Mejor: The Evolution of Puerto Rican Identity, Activism and Politics in New York City from 1950-1964". (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Xiao, Emily, "Between Incarceration and Care: Disability, Bureaucracy, and Citizenship in Japanese American Wartime Camps, 1942-1946". (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - The Percival W. Clement Prize
      - Augustine, John A., "Framing the Public: James J. Hill and the great Northern Railroad's Public-Benefit Strategy Between 1885-1917". (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Ramsden, Walter McLean, "Action Intellectuals and Responsible Bureaucracy in Twentieth-Century America: The Ideas and Institution-Building Projects of Carl Joachim Friedrich". (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - European prize winners
    - Andrew D. White European prize
      - Gurwitt, Sam, "The Egyptian Facade of the German Democratic Republic: Cultural Politics of East Berlin's Egyptian Museum, 1953-1989". (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Shimer, David, "The Stasi's Operation to Save Ostpolitik: Bribery, Corruption, and the Near Downfall of West German Chancellor Willy Brandt". (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Winfred Sturley Prize
      - Adler, Jonathan, "The Iraq Petroleum Company in Mandatory Palestine, 1927-1939". (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Walsh, Caitlin, "All that Glitters is Not Gold: The Rise and Fall of Early British Colonial Banking Schemes in Massachusetts, Jamaica and Barbados". (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - History of Science and Medicine prize winners
    - Martin Klein and George Rosen Prize
    - Ngo, Nealie, "The Body Issue: What Global and Historical Perspectives of the Ideal Female Body Can Teach Us About Our Own Present-Day Bodies". (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Wingerson, Mary, "Lunacy Under the Burden of Freedom: Race and Insanity in the American South, 1840-1890". (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Latin American, Africa, Asia & Middle East Prize
    - Andrew D. White Prize
      - Benares, Isabel, "Technocractic Rule Under Ferdinand Marcos: the Men Behind His "New Society"". (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Nasrallah, Lena, "Contested Space: Refugees, the Law, and the Shaping of Post-Partition Calcutta". (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - The Max Bildner Prize for Latin American History
      - Anderson, Elena, "Seven Million Colored Condoms: Population and Family Planning Initiatives in the Dominican Republic, 1965-1985". (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - Kuritzkes, Caroline, "Tourism, Democracy, and the Cuban Revolution after the Soviet Collapse: Economic Reform in the "Special Period", 1989-1995". (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - The Robert D. Gries Prize
      - Tan, Mitchell, "Spiritual Fraternities: The Transnational Networks of Ngo-Dinh Diem's Personalist Revolution and South Vietnam's Republic, 1955-1963". (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Other department prize winners
    - The American Jewish Congress Prize
      - Gutfreund, Hedy, "Somewhere in the Middle-Between: Opportunities and Limitations for Refugee Scholars at Black Colleges" (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Diane E. Kaplan Memorial Prize
      - Bernstein, Will, "From Paris to New Haven: Maurice Rotival and the Longue Duree of Urban Renewal". (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - The Obernauer Memorial Prize
      - Sweedler, Maya, "Why were you not Zusya": Maurice Freedman and the Americanization of Martin Buber"". (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - The Wolfgang Leonhard Prize in Russian and East Europe Studies
      - Sveshnikov, Stephan, "Politics and Daily Life at the First Session of the Sobor of 1917-1918". (Box 2, Folder 5)